JERUD Moyer

Software Developer



(503) 201-0100



jerudmoyer@gmail.com



<u>jerud-moyer</u>



Jerud-Moyer

ABOUT ME

Full-Stack software developer with a background in fine-arts and customer service. Blending creativity with code to solve problems and always striving to make the results beautiful. I value shared experiences with teammates and clients alike.

TECH SKILLS

languages

- JavaScript
- HTMI
- CSS

testing

- Jest
- QUnit
- SuperTest

frameworks

& libraries

- Node.js
- Express
- PostgreSQL
- React
- Redux
- BCrypt

EDUCATION

Alchemy Code Lab 2020

6 months of intense code immersion with focus on JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express and PostgreSQL. Here I learned many tools for advanced problem solving.

Portland Community College 1994 - 1997

Fine Arts, focused on life painting and drawing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Amphead-Lanham 2021

<u>site</u>

<u>github</u>

Software Developer

Designed and developed this full-stack web app for a multi-faceted Portland business. Amphead services musical equipment and Lanham builds custom guitar amplifiers. One website that acts as two. A NodeJS/Express backend API with PostgreSQL database, serves the data. A React/Redux front end brings it all to the consumer. Protected routes with full authorization allow the site owner to manage content through an administrator UI.

Alchemy Code Lab 2021-Present

Software Development Teaching Assistant
Teaching the next generation of developers. Focused on
JavaScript, React, Node.js and PostgreSQL.

Goldrush Coffee Bar 2004-2020

Owner / Operator

Community and quality were paramount to the vision. Here I learned many sides of small business operations including actively supporting the local community, hiring and management of staff, inventory management, bookkeeping, accounting and customer relations. Problem solving was the common thread woven throughout my many daily tasks. My intuition and experience served me well in creating this beloved gathering place.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Mood Music

React, Redux, Node, PostgreSQL, Heroku

site

github

An app that captures a user's mood and returns a perfect playlist. A webcam captures a still picture that is sent to the M.S. Azure facial recognition API for emotional analysis. The data received is then used to query the Spotify API which returns a playlist that is rendered in a widget for browser playability. This was built in a one week sprint. I implemented Redux for global state and wrote the logic for formulating the music query to ensure that results are relevant and varied. I also created the unique color gradient backgrounds that display based on the strongest emotion detected.

Project Vobot

Node, PostgreSQL, Jest, Heroku, Twilio, Twitter

site github

In a four day remote sprint, my team and I built a pair of bots to deliver state-specific voter information to users. We built a webscraper to supply our data. We then created Twitter and SMS bots to reply to a user's request with information relevant to their home state. Each time a targeted Twitter account tweets, the Twitter bot responds with a randomly selected quote in support of democracy with instructions on how to receive voter information from either bot. I built the SMS functionality using Twilio, as well as building and curating the quote database.